<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>EURAC Research on All4Ling</title><link>https://commul.github.io/all4ling/contributors/eurac-research/</link><description>Recent content in EURAC Research on All4Ling</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-EN</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:50:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://commul.github.io/all4ling/contributors/eurac-research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Zeit.shift MOOC -Digital in gesterns Zukunft- goes online! 👩🏼‍🏫</title><link>https://commul.github.io/all4ling/blog/2022-05-05/zeit.shift-mooc-digital-in-gesterns-zukunft-goes-online/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 06:00:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://commul.github.io/all4ling/blog/2022-05-05/zeit.shift-mooc-digital-in-gesterns-zukunft-goes-online/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re very happy to announce that the Zeit.shift e-learning course (MOOC) is now online!
What do newspapers tell us about life 100 years ago? How can I research historical newspapers available online to formulate a scholarly question? How are newspapers digitized and made accessible via web platforms?
In the Zeit.shift MOOC &amp;ldquo;Digital in yesterday&amp;rsquo;s future&amp;rdquo; you will work with digitised historical newspapers from North, East and South Tyrol made available online for scholarly research.</description></item><item><title>Unterinntaler Bote adverts added to Historypin📍</title><link>https://commul.github.io/all4ling/blog/2022-04-11/unterinntaler-bote-adverts-added-to-historypin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 06:00:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://commul.github.io/all4ling/blog/2022-04-11/unterinntaler-bote-adverts-added-to-historypin/</guid><description>A new collection of 110 historical advertisements from the Unterinntaler Bote newspaper is now available in Historypin! This newspaper was published in Hall in Tirol, North Tyrol, between 1892 and 1916 and the adverts you&amp;rsquo;ll find online were extracted from the 1900 issue.
Start tagging!</description></item><item><title>Schwazer Lokalanzeiger adverts added to Historypin📍</title><link>https://commul.github.io/all4ling/blog/2022-04-04/schwazer-lokalanzeiger-adverts-added-to-historypin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 06:00:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://commul.github.io/all4ling/blog/2022-04-04/schwazer-lokalanzeiger-adverts-added-to-historypin/</guid><description>A new collection of 203 historical advertisements from the Schwazer Lokalanzeiger Kreisblatt newspaper is now available in Historypin! This newspaper was published in Schwaz, North Tyrol, between 1927 and 1938 and the adverts you&amp;rsquo;ll find online were extracted from the 1928 issue.
Check out our previous blogpost for some recent radio and TV coverage of Zeit.shift in Schwaz!
Start tagging!</description></item><item><title>Zeit.shift makes the Austrian news 📺</title><link>https://commul.github.io/all4ling/blog/2022-03-08/zeit.shift-makes-the-austrian-news/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 06:00:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://commul.github.io/all4ling/blog/2022-03-08/zeit.shift-makes-the-austrian-news/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re proud to share that ORF.AT, the Austrian national public service broadcaster, has featured Zeit.shift in both a TV and a radio interview! In these interviews, Johanna Walcher and Maritta Horwath provide an overview of the project and illustrate how citizens can get involved.
Watch the TV interview here: tvthek.orf.at
Listen to the radio interview here: radiothek.orf.at
Enjoy!😊
When you're done, join us and other citizens on Historypin to help locate and tag historical trade in Tyrol!</description></item><item><title>CitSci 2022 proposal accepted🎓</title><link>https://commul.github.io/all4ling/blog/2022-02-07/citsci-2022-proposal-accepted/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 06:00:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://commul.github.io/all4ling/blog/2022-02-07/citsci-2022-proposal-accepted/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re delighted to share that our proposal to present a Zeit.shift demo at the Engaging Citizen Science Conference 2022 has been accepted!
In this demo, which will take place on April 25th in Aarhus, participants will have the chance to explore and engage with the citizen science tasks developed for the project.
The full conference programme is available at: https://conferences.au.dk/citsci2022/programme/</description></item></channel></rss>